http://typo3.org/privacy-policy

1. An overview of data protectionGeneral informationThe following information will provide you with an easy to navigate overview of what will happen with your personal data when you visit our website. The term “personal data” comprises all data that can be used to personally identify you. For detailed information about the subject matter of data protection, please consult our Data Protection Declaration, which we have included beneath this copy.Data recording on our websiteWho is the responsible party for the recording of data on this website (i.e. the “controller”)?The data on this website is processed by the operator of the website, whose contact information is available under section “Information Required by Law” on this website.How do we record your data?We collect your data as a result of your sharing of your data with us. This may, for instance be information you enter into our contact form.Our IT systems automatically record other data when you visit our website. This data comprises primarily technical information (e.g. web browser, operating system or time the site was accessed). This information is recorded automatically when you access our website.What are the purposes we use your data for?A portion of the information is generated to guarantee the error free provision of the website. Other data may be used to analyse your user patterns.What rights do you have as far as your information is concerned?You have the right to receive information about the source, recipients and purposes of your archived personal data at any time without having to pay a fee for such disclosures. You also have the right to demand that your data are rectified, blocked or eradicated. Please do not hesitate to contact us at any time under the address disclosed in section “Information Required by Law” on this website if you have questions about this or any other data protection related issues. You also have the right to log a complaint with the competent supervising agency.Moreover, under certain circumstances, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data. For details, please consult the Data Protection Declaration under section “Right to Restriction of Data Processing.”Analysis tools and tools provided by third partiesThere is a possibility that your browsing patterns will be statistically analysed when your visit our website. Such analyses are performed primarily with cookies and with what we refer to as analysis programmes. As a rule, the analyses of your browsing patterns are conducted anonymously; i.e. the browsing patterns cannot be traced back to you. You have the option to object to such analyses or you can prevent their performance by not using certain tools. For detailed information about this, please consult our Data Protection Declaration below.You do have the option to object to such analyses. We will brief you on the objection options in this Data Protection Declaration.2. General information and mandatory informationData protectionThe operators of this website and its pages take the protection of your personal data very seriously. Hence, we handle your personal data as confidential information and in compliance with the statutory data protection regulations and this Data Protection Declaration.Whenever you use this website, a variety of personal information will be collected. Personal data comprises data that can be used to personally identify you. This Data Protection Declaration explains which data we collect as well as the purposes we use this data for. It also explains how, and for which purpose the information is collected.We herewith advise you that the transmission of data via the Internet (i.e. through e-mail communications) may be prone to security gaps. It is not possible to completely protect data against third party access.Information about the responsible party (referred to as the “controller” in the GDPR)The data processing controller on this website is:TYPO3 Association Herr Olivier Dobberkau / President Sihlbruggstrasse 105 6340 Baar SwitzerlandTelephone: +41 41 511 00 35 Email: info(at)typo3.orgThe controller is the natural person or legal entity that single-handedly or jointly with others makes decisions as to the purposes of and resources for the processing of personal data (e.g. names, e-mail addresses, etc.).Revocation of your consent to the processing of dataA wide range of data processing transactions are possible only subject to your express consent. You can also revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.Right to object to the collection of data in special cases; right to object to direct advertising (Art. 21 GDPR)In the event that data are processed on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. e or f GDPR, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your personal data based on grounds arising from your unique situation. This also applies to any profiling based on these provisions. To determine the legal basis, on which any processing of data is based, please consult this Data Protection Declaration. If you log an objection, we will no longer process your affected personal data, unless we are in a position to present compelling protection worthy grounds for the processing of your data, that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms or if the purpose of the processing is the claiming, exercising or defence of legal entitlements (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR).If your personal data is being processed in order to engage in direct advertising, you have the right to at any time object to the processing of your affected personal data for the purposes of such advertising. This also applies to profiling to the extent that it is affiliated with such direct advertising. If you object, your personal data will subsequently no longer be used for direct advertising purposes (objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 2 GDPR).Right to log a complaint with the competent supervisory agencyIn the event of violations of the GDPR, data subjects are entitled to log a complaint with a supervisory agency, in particular in the member state where they usually maintain their domicile, place of work or at the place where the alleged violation occurred. The right to log a complaint is in effect regardless of any other administrative or court proceedings available as legal recourses.Right to data portabilityYou have the right to demand that we hand over any data we automatically process on the basis of your consent or in order to fulfil a contract be handed over to you or a third party in a commonly used, machine readable format. If you should demand the direct transfer of the data to another controller, this will be done only if it is technically feasible.SSL and/or TLS encryptionFor security reasons and to protect the transmission of confidential content, such as purchase orders or inquiries you submit to us as the website operator, this website uses either an SSL or a TLS encryption programme. You can recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the browser switches from “http://” to “https://” and also by the appearance of the lock icon in the browser line.If the SSL or TLS encryption is activated, data you transmit to us cannot be read by third parties.Encrypted payment transactions on this websiteIf you are under an obligation to share your payment information (e.g. account number if you give us the authority to debit your bank account) with us after you have entered into a fee-based contract with us, this information is required to process payments.Payment transactions using common modes of paying (Visa/MasterCard, debit to your bank account) are processed exclusively via encrypted SSL or TLS connections. You can recognise an encrypted connection by checking whether the address line of the browser switches from “http://” to “https://” and also by the appearance of the lock icon in the browser line.If the communication with us is encrypted, third parties will not be able to read the payment information you share with us.Information about, blockage, rectification and eradication of dataWithin the scope of the applicable statutory provisions, you have the right to at any time demand information about your archived personal data, their source and recipients as well as the purpose of the processing of your data. You may also have a right to have your data rectified, blocked or eradicated. If you have questions about this subject matter or any other questions about personal data, please do not hesitate to contact us at any time at the address provided in section “Information Required by Law.”Right to demand processing restrictionsYou have the right to demand the imposition of restrictions as far as the processing of your personal data is concerned. To do so, you may contact us at any time at the address provided in section “Information Required by Law.” The right to demand restriction of processing applies in the following cases:In the event that you should dispute the correctness of your data archived by us, we will usually need some time to verify this claim. During the time that this investigation is ongoing, you have the right to demand that we restrict the processing of your personal data.If the processing of your personal data was/is conducted in an unlawful manner, you have the option to demand the restriction of the processing of your data in lieu of demanding the eradication of this data.If we do not need your personal data any longer and you need it to exercise, defend or claim legal entitlements, you have the right to demand the restriction of the processing of your personal data instead of its eradication.If you have raised an objection pursuant to Art. 21 Sect. 1 GDPR, your rights and our rights will have to be weighed against each other. As long as it has not been determined whose interests prevail, you have the right to demand a restriction of the processing of your personal data.If you have restricted the processing of your personal data, these data – with the exception of their archiving – may be processed only subject to your consent or to claim, exercise or defend legal entitlements or to protect the rights of other natural persons or legal entities or for important public interest reasons cited by the European Union or a member state of the EU.3. Data protection officerDesignation of a data protection officer as mandated by lawWe have appointed a data protection officer for our company.The data protection officer of the TYPO3 Association is provided by Computer-Zauber Dipl.-Ing. Karen Falkenberg Erlentiefenstraße 54 59192 Bergkamen GermanyTelephone: +49 (0) 2307 80102 Email: privacy(at)typo3.org4. Recording of data on our websiteCookiesIn some instances, our website and its pages use so-called cookies. Cookies do not cause any damage to your computer and do not contain viruses. The purpose of cookies is to make our website more user friendly, effective and more secure. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer and stored by your browser.Most of the cookies we use are so-called “session cookies.” They are automatically deleted after your leave our site. Other cookies will remain archived on your device until you delete them. These cookies enable us to recognise your browser the next time you visit our website.You can adjust the settings of your browser to make sure that you are notified every time cookies are placed and to enable you to accept cookies only in specific cases or to exclude the acceptance of cookies for specific situations or in general and to activate the automatic deletion of cookies when you close your browser. If you deactivate cookies, the functions of this website may be limited.Cookies that are required for the performance of the electronic communications transaction or to provide certain functions you want to use (e.g. the shopping cart function), are stored on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in storing cookies to ensure the technically error free and optimised provision of the operator’s services. If other cookies (e.g. cookies for the analysis of your browsing patterns) should be stored, they are addressed separately in this Data Protection Declaration.Server log filesThe provider of this website and its pages automatically collects and stores information in so-called server log files, which your browser communicates to us automatically. The information comprises:The type and version of browser usedThe used operating systemReferrer URLThe hostname of the accessing computerThe time of the server inquiryThe IP addressThis data is not merged with other data sources.This data is recorded on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the technically error free depiction and the optimization of the operator’s website. In order to achieve this, server log files must be recorded.Contact formIf you submit inquiries to us via our contact form, the information provided in the contact form as well as any contact information provided therein will be stored by us in order to handle your inquiry and in the event that we have further questions. We will not share this information without your consent.Hence, the processing of the data entered into the contact form occurs exclusively based on your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.The information you have entered into the contact form shall remain with us until you ask us to eradicate the data, revoke your consent to the archiving of data or if the purpose for which the information is being archived no longer exists (e.g. after we have concluded our response to your inquiry). This shall be without prejudice to any mandatory legal provisions – in particular retention periods.Registration on this websiteYou have the option to register on our website to be able to use additional website functions. We shall use the data you enter only for the purpose of using the respective offer or service you have registered for. The required information we request at the time of registration must be entered in full. Otherwise we shall reject the registration.To notify you of any important changes to the scope of our portfolio or in the event of technical modifications, we shall use the e-mail address provided during the registration process.We shall process the data entered during the registration process on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.The data recorded during the registration process shall be stored by us as long as you are registered on our website. Subsequently, such data shall be deleted. This shall be without prejudice to mandatory statutory retention obligations.The comment function on this websiteWhen you use the comment function on this website, information on the time the comment was generated and, if you are not posting anonymously, the user name you have selected will be archived in addition to your comments.Subscribing to commentsAs a user of this website, you have the option to subscribe to comments after you have registered. You will receive a confirmation e-mail, the purpose of which is to verify whether you are the actual holder of the provided e-mail address. You can deactivate this function at any time by following a respective link in the information e-mails. The data entered in conjunction with subscriptions to comments will be deleted in this case. However, if you have communicated this information to us for other purposes and from a different location (e.g. when subscribing to the newsletter), the data shall remain in our possession.Storage period for commentsComments and any affiliated information (e.g. the IP address) shall be stored by us and remain on our website until the content the comment pertained to has been deleted in its entirety or if the comments had to be deleted for legal reasons (e.g. insulting comments).Legal basisComments are stored on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You have the right to revoke at any time any consent you have already given us. To do so, all you are required to do is sent us an informal notification via e-mail. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data collection that occurred prior to your revocation.Processing of data (customer and contract data)We collect, process and use personal data only to the extent necessary for the establishment, content organization or change of the legal relationship (data inventory). These actions are taken on the basis of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR, which permits the processing of data for the fulfilment of a contract or pre-contractual actions. We collect, process and use personal data concerning the use of our website (usage data) only to the extent that this is necessary to make it possible for users to utilize the services and to bill for them.The collected customer data shall be eradicated upon completion of the order or the termination of the business relationship. This shall be without prejudice to any statutory retention mandates.Data transfer upon closing of contracts for services and digital contentWe share personal data with third parties only if this is necessary in conjunction with the handling of the contract; for instance, with the financial institution tasked with the processing of payments.Any further transfer of data shall not occur or shall only occur if you have expressly consented to the transfer. Any sharing of your data with third parties in the absence of your express consent, for instance for advertising purposes, shall not occur.The basis for the processing of data is Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR, which permits the processing of data for the fulfilment of a contract or for pre-contractual actions.5. Social mediaFacebook plug-ins (Like & Share button)We have integrated plug-ins of the social network Facebook, provided by Facebook Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, California 94025, USA, on our website. You will be able to recognise Facebook plug-ins by the Facebook logo or the "Like" button on our website. An overview of the Facebook plug-ins is available under the following link: https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/.Whenever you visit our website and its pages, the plug-in will establish a direct connection between your browser and the Facebook server. As a result, Facebook will receive the information that you have visited our website with your plug-in. However, if you click the Facebook “Like” button while you are logged into your Facebook account, you can link the content of our website and its pages with your Facebook profile. As a result, Facebook will be able to allocate the visit to our website and its pages to your Facebook user account. We have to point out, that we as the provider of the website do not have any knowledge of the transferred data and its use by Facebook. For more detailed information, please consult the Data Privacy Declaration of Facebook at: https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.If you do not want Facebook to be able to allocate your visit to our website and its pages to your Facebook user account, please log out of your Facebook account while you are on our website.The use of the Facebook plug-in is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in being as visible as possible on social media.Twitter plug-inWe have integrated functions of the social media platform Twitter into our website. These functions are provided by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. While you use Twitter and the "Re-Tweet" function, websites you visit are linked to your Twitter account and disclosed to other users. During this process, data are transferred to Twitter as well. We must point out, that we, the providers of the website and its pages do not know anything about the content of the data transferred and the use of this information by Twitter. For more details, please consult Twitter’s Data Privacy Declaration at: https://twitter.com/en/privacy.The use of Twitter plug-ins is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in being as visible as possible on social media.You have the option to reset your data protection settings on Twitter under the account settings at https://twitter.com/account/settings.Google+ plug-inOur website and its pages use functions of Google+; the provider is Google Ireland Limited (“Google”), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.Recording and sharing of information: With the assistance of the Google+ button, you can publish information worldwide. The Google+ button provides you and other users with custom tailored Google content as well as content of our partners. Google saves the information you have entered for content with +1 as well as information about the website/page you viewed when you clicked on +1. Your +1 entries may appear as information along with your profile name and your photo on Google services, such as in search results or in your Google profile or in other locations on websites and ads on the Internet.Google records information about your +1 activities to improve Google’s services for you and others. To be able to use the Google+ button, you will need a public Google profile, which is visible around the world, which must contain at least the name you have chosen for your profile. This name is used in conjunction with all Google services. In some cases, this name may also replace another name you have used when sharing content via your Google account. The identity of your Google profile may be displayed to users who know your e-mail address or are in possession of other information related to you that identifies you.Use of the recorded information: Besides the abovementioned purposes of use, the information you provide is also used in compliance with the applicable Google Data Privacy Policies. Google may potentially publish summary statistics about the +1 activities of its users or shares this information with users and partners, such as publishers, prospective customers or affiliated websites.The use of the Google+ plug-in is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The operator of the website has a legitimate interest in being as visible as possible on social media.6. Analysis tools and advertisingMatomo (formerly called Piwik)This website uses the open source web analysis service Matomo. Matomo uses so-called “cookies,” which are text files that are stored on your computer and that make it possible to analyse your use of this website. In conjunction with this, the information about the use of this website generated by the cookie will be archived on our server. Prior to archiving, the IP address will first be anonymized.Matomo cookies will remain on your device until you delete them.The storage of Matomo cookies and the use of this analysis tool are based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The website operator has a legitimate interest in the analysis of user patterns, in order to optimize the operator’s web offerings and advertising.The information generated by cookies concerning the use of this website shall not be shared with any third parties. You may prevent the storage of cookies at any time by making pertinent changes to your browser software settings; however, we have to point out that in this case you may not be able to use all of the functions of this website to their fullest extent.If you do not consent to the storage and use of your data, you have the option to deactivate the storage and use of such data here. In this case, an opt out cookie will be placed in our browser, which prevent the storage of usage data by Matomo. If you delete your cookies, this will also result in the deletion of the Matomo opt out cookie. Hence, you will have to reactivate the opt out when you return to visit our website.Opt out Matomo tracking
Google Analytics RemarketingThis website uses the functions of Google Analytics Remarketing in combination with the functions of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick, which work on all devices. The provider of these solutions is Google Ireland Limited („Google“), Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland.This function makes it possible to connect the advertising target groups generated with Google Analytics Remarketing with the functions of Google AdWords and Google DoubleClick, which work on all devices. This makes it possible to display interest-based customized advertising messages, depending on your prior usage and browsing patterns on a device (e.g. cell phone) in a manner tailored to you as well as on any of your devices (e.g. tablet or PC).If you have given us pertinent consent, Google will connect your web and app browser progressions with your Google account for this purpose. As a result, it is possible to display the same personalized advertising messages on every device you log into with your Google account.To support this function, Google Analytics records Google authenticated IDs of users that are temporarily connected with our Google Analytics data to define and compile the target groups for the ads to be displayed on all devices.You have the option to permanently object to remarketing/targeting across all devices by deactivating personalized advertising. To do this, please follow this link: https://www.google.com/settings/ads/onweb/.The consolidation of the recorded data in your Google account shall occur exclusively based on your consent, which you may give to Google and also revoke there (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). Data recording processes that are not consolidated in your Google account (for instance because you do not have a Google account or have objected to the consolidation of data), the recording of data is based on Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. The legitimate interest arises from the fact that the operator of the website has a legitimate interest in the anonymized analysis of website visitor for advertising purposes.For further information and the pertinent data protection regulations, please consult the Data Privacy Policies of Google at: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads?hl=en.7. NewsletterNewsletter dataIf you would like to subscribe to the newsletter offered on this website, we will need from you an e-mail address as well as information that allow us to verify that you are the owner of the e-mail address provided and consent to the receipt of the newsletter. No further data shall be collected or shall be collected only on a voluntary basis. We shall use such data only for the sending of the requested information and shall not share such data with any third parties.The processing of the information entered into the newsletter subscription form shall occur exclusively on the basis of your consent (Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR). You may revoke the consent you have given to the archiving of data, the e-mail address and the use of this information for the sending of the newsletter at any time, for instance by clicking on the „Unsubscribe“ link in the newsletter. This shall be without prejudice to the lawfulness of any data processing transactions that have taken place to date.The data deposited with us for the purpose of subscribing to the newsletter will be stored by us until you unsubscribe from the newsletter or the newsletter service provider and deleted from the newsletter distribution list after you unsubscribe from the newsletter. Data stored for other purposes with us remain unaffected.After you unsubscribe from the newsletter distribution list, your e-mail address may be stored by us or the newsletter service provider in a blacklist to prevent future mailings. The data from the blacklist is used only for this purpose and not merged with other data. This serves both your interest and our interest in complying with the legal requirements when sending newsletters (legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR). The storage in the blacklist is indefinite. You may object to the storage if your interests outweigh our legitimate interest.8. Plug-ins and ToolsYouTube with expanded data protection integrationattempts to commit fraud. These cookies will stay on your device until you delete them.Under certain circumstances, additional data processing transactions may be triggered after you have started to play a YouTube video, which are beyond our control.The use of YouTube is based on our interest in presenting our online content in an appealing manner. Pursuant to Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR, this is a legitimate interest. If a corresponding agreement has been requested (e.g. an agreement to the storage of cookies), the processing takes place exclusively on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR; the agreement can be revoked at any time.For more information on how YouTube handles user data, please consult the YouTube Data Privacy Policy under: https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en.Google Web Fonts (local embedding)This website uses so-called Web Fonts provided by Google to ensure the uniform use of fonts on this site. These Google fonts are locally installed so that a connection to Google’s servers will not be established in conjunction with this application.Retrieval of profile pictures from GravatarIn order to display the logged-in visitor on the internal typo3.org area, as well as for displaying the author picture in the news area and user listings the online service Gravatar by Automattic Inc. 60 29th Street #343 San Francisco, CA 94110 United States of America, is used.Gravatar is a service where users can log in and store profile images and their email addresses. If users use the respective email address on other online services to comment or publish content their profile pictures can be displayed next to the posts or activities. For this purpose, the email address provided by the users is sent to Gravatar to check whether a profile is connected with it. This is the only purpose of transmitting the email address. Email addresses are not used for other purposes and deleted afterwards.The use of Gravatar is based on our legitimate interests in the sense of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. With the help of Gravatar we offer the news authors as well as the users of the internal area the chance to personalize their contributions and their commitment to TYPO3 with a profile picture.In order to display the images Gravatar finds out the user’s IP address as this is necessary for the communication between the browser and the online service.Further information on the collection and use of the data by Gravatar can be found in the privacy policy of Automattic Inc.: https://automattic.com/privacy/.If users do not want a user image linked to their email address at Gravatar in the internal TYPO3 area or other frontend services, an email address not stored at Gravatar should be used to register. We also point out that it is possible to use an anonymous email address if users do not want their own email address transmitted to Gravatar. Users can completely prevent the transfer of data by not using our internal service area and don't post any news articles.PodcastsWe use the podcast hosting service buzzsprout from the Provider Higher Pixels, Inc., 5133 San Jose Blvd., Jacksonville, FL 32207 USA. The podcasts are hosted at buzzsprout.com and integrated into our pages. When playing a podcast, it is retrieved from buzzsprout.com. Buzzsprout processes IP addresses and device information to enable podcast downloads and playback and to determine statistical data such as download numbers. This data is anonymized or pseudonymized by buzzsprout before it is stored in the database, provided that it is not necessary for the provision of the podcasts. The use of Buzzsprout is due to our legitimate interest in including podcasts in our site. The legal basis for processing is therefore Article 6 Section (1) (f) GDPR. For more information and to object, please refer to buzzsprout's privacy policy.Google Tag ManagerThis website uses the Google Tag Manager. This solution offers the possibility to manage all website tags via one interface. No cookies are set, only tags that do not collect personal data. The tag manager may be able to activate other tags that may collect data. However, the Google Tag Manager cannot retrieve and evaluate such data. Set domain or cookie deactivations remain for all Google Tracking Tags. The use of the Google Tag Manager is in the interest of presenting an optimized online offering. This constitutes a legitimate interest within the meaning of Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. f GDPR. More information on the handling of user data can be found in the Google Tag Manager privacy policy: http://www.google.de/tagmanager/use-policy.html9. Payment service providers and resellersPayPalAmong other options, we offer payment via PayPal on this website. The provider of this payment processing service is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. et Cie, S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, L-2449 Luxembourg (hereinafter referred to as „PayPal“).If you choose payment via PayPal, we will share the payment information you enter with PayPal.The legal basis for the sharing of your data with PayPal is Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. a GDPR (consent) as well as Art. 6 Sect. 1 lit. b GDPR (processing for the fulfilment of a contract). You have the option to at any time revoke your consent to the processing of your data. Such a revocation shall not have any impact on the effectiveness of data processing transactions that occurred in the past.
Last update: 30 November 2020
